

Karsten Held Applications Architect C# Developer Freelancer

Currently looking to work as a contractor in SharePoint and .NET application development projects.

Karsten Held Rothenburger Straße 32 D-10099 DRESDEN

4 +49 176 70861670

karsten.held@aufgang.org

www.karstenheld.com

Personal Profile

An enthusiastic, energetic and hard working software architect who is able to design complex business solutions using Microsoft SharePoint and Office platforms. Experience in data integration and cross-platform projects using web-based APIs. Possessing extensive knowledge of fund management and trading processes. 8 years experience in designing and programming business applications with focus on usability and performance. Profound knowledge of web design and development.

Areas of expertise

- Designing Mid- to large-scale intranet solutions using Microsoft SharePoint
- Hybrid-Cloud solutions and integration of LOB Applications in Microsoft SharePoint
- Office 365 Apps & Add-Ins
- SharePoint WebParts
- WinForms, WPF/XAML, Silverlight
- HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript

Microsoft Certified

- Twitter Bootstrap
- Java Swing, Vaadin
- Bloomberg API

Career History

JAN 2013 - present

Freelancer

- 2013 Avalain, Budapest: Design and programming of a web application with focus on usability.
 The design takes into account various features of the Vaadin framework.
- 2013 <u>Bencer</u>, Shanghai: SharePoint Online Solution for publishing realtime pictures of construction sites. Several project sites for online collaboration.

JUL 2012 - DEC 2012

Consultant at Communardo Software GmbH, Dresden

 Analysis of customer needs and specification of corporate intranet solutions using SharePoint 2012 Server for clients like <u>Axel Springer AG</u> and <u>Voestalpine Group</u>.

NOV 2008 - MAY 2012

Freelancer

- 2010 2012 Concept and prototyping of several web applications for Osyon Gmbh, Berlin.
- 2009 2012 Design and programming of website and software tools for Bencer, Shanghai.
- 2009 Thomson-Reuters data integration using an Excel-Add-In (VBA) for <u>financial.com</u>
- 2008 2009 Concept and design of a portfolio management software for <u>Vescore</u>, Munich.

JAN 2001 – AUG 2008

Project Manager at Vescore Solutions AG

- 2006 2008 Development of a asset management infrastructure consisting of databases, server applications, portfolio management tools and Excel-based custom solutions.
- 2004 2006 Management of several global investment funds (Value, Listed Private Equity).
 Development of trading tools (Excel, VBA, C#) based on the Bloomberg Terminal API.
- 2003 2007 Development of the Portfolio Monitor (C#), a portfolio and risk management solution for hedgefunds and overlays with real-time risk and value-at-risk calculation.
- 2001 2003 Design and programming of Market Navigator (Java, Swing, C#, SOAP). A client-server application that visualizes complex model-based return forecasts.

MAR 2000 - DEC 2000

Developer at Dr. Grob & Partner AG, Winterthur

 Design and prototyping of a bridge and tunnel management system (Visual Basic 6) based on the swiss bridge and tunnel database (ORACLE).

Education

MAY 2013 OCT 1994 – FEB 2000 OCT 1997 – FEB 2000 LANGUAGES MCP Test 331 Core Technologies for Microsoft SharePoint Server 2013
Master of Civil Engineering (Dipl.-Ing) at <u>Bauhaus-University Weimar</u>
Media Design at <u>Bauhaus-University Weimar</u>

German, English, Hungarian